apn-gcr.org 2016-05-10

# Privacy Policy | Asia-Pacific Network for Global Change Research

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, the APN collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. The APN’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how the APN’s visitors use its Website.

The APN also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. The APN does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to the APN Website choose to interact with the APN in ways that require the APN to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that the APN gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who use our forums to provide a username and email address. In each case, the APN collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfil the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with the APN. The APN does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

The APN discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on the APN’s behalf or to provide services available at the APN’s Website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using the APN Website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. The APN will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations, as described above, the APN discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when the APN believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of the APN, third parties, or the public at large. The APN takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. The APN uses cookies to help the APN identify and track visitors, their usage of the APN Website, and their website access preferences. The APN Website visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using the APN’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of the APN’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, the APN may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in the APN’s sole discretion. The APN encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
